# 大家好 我是王刚
Hello, this is Chef Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
Today, I will share a recipe with you.
# 鲜椒千层肚
Chili Beef Tripe
# 首先我们准备千层肚400克
First, we get 400g of beef tripe (omasum, aka book/leaf tripe)
# 将千层肚从中间切开之后再翻面横切成细丝备用
After cutting it in half, we slice it into strips.
# 不喜欢细丝的同学也可以将其改刀切成片
If you don't like thin strips, you can cut the stomach into slices.
# 然后将切好的千层肚放入盆中
Then, we put them into a big bowl
# 盆中再加入适量的清水没过千层肚
We add water into the bowl until the tripe slices are submerged.
# 加入白醋40克搅拌均匀浸泡10分钟备用
Add 40g white vinegar and soak for 10 min.
# 这一步的目的是中和千层肚的碱性
This will neutralize the alkalinity of the tripe
# 同时也减少千层肚的异味
and remove the tripe's unpleasant odor
# 下一步开始准备垫底的辅料
Now, let's prepare the minor ingredients.
# 准备大白菜几片用手撕成小片备用
Tear apart a few Napa cabbage leaves in to small pieces.
# 准备凤尾1颗切成小条备用
Cut a Feng Wei (Chinese lettuce) into strips.
# 准备适量的黄豆芽放入碗中备用
Put some soy bean sprouts into a bowl.
# 最后准备几根香芹切成小段备用
Finally, some Chinese celery.
# 下一步开始准备料头
Now, let's make the aromatics.
# 准备大蒜和仔姜各30克切成片备用
Slice some garlic and young ginger, 30g each.
# 准备小米辣30克切成片备用
And slice 30g of "Xiaomila" chili pepper.
# 准备二荆条几根切成小片备用（约40克）
Slice some "Erjingtiao" chili pepper (about 40g).
# 准备油泡（鲜）青花椒30克备用
Prepare 30g of fresh (or oil-soaked) green Sichuan peppercorns.
# 最后准备火锅底料35克切散备用
Finally, break down 35g of hot-pot base.
# 不喜欢红汤的同学可以不加火锅底料
For those who don't like hot soup, you don't have to add the hot-pot base.
# 也可以改用鸡汁代替
You can also replace it with chicken stock concentrate.
# 10分钟之后将千层肚捞出沥干水份备用
After 10min, take out the tripe and squeeze out the excess water.
# 下一步开始制作
Now, let's start cooking.
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水开大火烧开
First, we add some water into the wok.
# 中途加入一大勺食用盐（约5克）
We then add a big spoon of salt (5g).
# 大火烧开之后将所有准备好的垫底辅料下锅焯水2分钟
When the water starts boiling, parboil all of the minor ingredients.
# 这一步的目的是将辅料煮至断生
This step will soften those ingredients.
# 辅料下锅之后再加入适量的植物油
Add some vegetable oil into the wok.
# 焯水2分钟之后捞出放入盆中垫底备用
After blanching for 2min, take out the vegetables and put them in the serving bowl.
# 锅中再次加入适量的清水烧开
We add water into the wok again until boiling.
# 中途加入少许的白醋
Add some white vinegar as well.
# 然后将千层肚下锅烫10秒钟
Put the stomach in for 10 sec.
# 同学们切记这一步的目的不是将千层肚煮熟
Remember, this step is not to cook the stomach thoroughly，
# 而是去除一些异味
but to remove some unpleasant smell.
# 10秒钟之后倒出控水备用
After 10sec, take out the stomach and leak out the excess water.
# 下一步开始制作红汤
Now, let's make the hot soup.
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, we heat up the wok.
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的植物油（约35克）
Then, we add some vegetable oil (35g).
# 油温4成热之后将准备好的所有料头下锅（姜蒜片、火锅底料、青花椒）
Heat up the wok to 40% and add all of the condiments (ginger, garlic, hot-pot base, green peppercorns).
# 料头下锅之后转中小火将其炒香炒化
Turn down the stove and stir-fry.
# 底料炒化之后加入适量的清水开大火烧开
After the hot-pot base melts, add water and turn up the stove.
# 大火烧开之后开始调味
After the soup boils, we start seasoning.
# 锅中加入食用盐1勺（约4克）
Add 4g of salt.
# 加入少许白糖
Some sugar.
# 加入胡椒粉1勺（约1克）
1g of ground white pepper.
# 加入味精1勺（约2克）
2g of MSG.
# 调好味之后将准备好的鲜辣椒和千层肚下锅烫30秒钟
After that, put the stomach, along with "Xiaomila" and "Erjingtiao" into the soup for 30 sec.
# 同学们千层肚不适合煮太久否则容易变老
The stomach will taste tough if we boil it for too long.
# 然后在起锅之前再加入适量的藤椒油（约4克）
Then, add 4g of green chili oil.
# 30秒钟之后将其捞出放入盆中
After 30 sec, we take everything out and put them into the bowl.
# 最后再加入适量的原汤
Finally, we add some broth.
# 一道非常美味的鲜椒千层肚就制作完成
A delicious Chili Beef Tripe is finished!
# 下面开始技术总结 第三，千层肚不能煮太久，否则容易缩水变得难嚼
Now, let's start the summary
1: We can either slice or julienne the tripe.
2: We can used chicken stock instead of hot-pot base.
3: We can't cook the tripe for too long, otherwise the texture will be too tough
That's it for the summary.